Divyang Shah

32, Somnath Society,

Odhav, Ahmedabad

07433860888

divyang.divyangshah.shah@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To foster the growth of an organization I will use technical and creative business skills. To seek a career in an exciting and ever challenging environment that will help in continuous up gradation of my skills and contribute to the organization's growth

PROFILE SUMMARY

A Critical Thinker With A Hunger For Personal And Professional Growth.

Remarkably knowledgeable, skilful and resourceful 12 years experience of IT, Market Research, Hospitality & BPO industries in ensuring the smooth running of the office and related areas, maintaining a high level of Client satisfaction, supervising, training and motivating the team.

Summary of Qualifications

- 1. A client services affinity
- 2. Good computer skills
- 3. Good administration skills
- 4. Good written communication skills
- 5. Leadership qualities and experience of managing a team of 10 BDEs and Web Researchers.
- 6. Work easily under pressure
- 7. Handle various projects at one time
- 8. Adhere to deadlines and targets set per project
- 9. Practical knowledge about the database tools, web sites and reports

CAREER PROFILE

- Provides best Client Satisfaction and on demand Service to the Client as per their requirements
- Professional and work oriented
- Also worked in high end BPO & Market Research Projects in regard to Customer Support, Sales, Marketing & Research
- More than 8 Years of total work experience

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - 12+ years

Senior Manager - Business Development

Ace Infoway Private Limited

October 2020 to April 2021

Primary responsibilities:

Managing end to end sales process along with project management till the delivery with after sales support.

Managing and grooming BDE & Web Researcher Team Identifying new sales leads Pitching products and/or services Maintaining fruitful relationships with existing customers

Day-to-day duties typically include:

Serving as the primary contact for the onboarding of new customers, satisfying their requirements, as well as post go-live support.

Connecting with the prospects to deliver predictable outcomes and experiences for their clients and predictable growth for their business.

Provide insights to customers to ensure that they get the most out of the platform with the aim of helping grow our customer base along with growing customer's business.

Driving retention and growth among our most valuable customers by understanding their business needs and helping them succeed.

Being the trusted person for the customers in terms of keeping them happy by delivering the expected results on their projects.

Collaborate with the engineering and development team to deliver the results as per customers' requirements and troubleshoot technical issues raised by customers.

Gauge customers' levels of engagement with the company and provide feedback to the other teams regarding product and service improvements.

Delivering and communicating ROI for our clients, throughout the customer lifecycle.

Collaborate closely with team members to support renewals and expansion opportunities.

Other typical duties include:

Develop a growth strategy focused both on financial gain and customer satisfaction Provide trustworthy feedback and after-sales support Develop entry level staff into valuable salespeople

Sr. Business Development Manager

Infusion Analysts Private Limited 2020

April 2018 to September

Primary responsibilities:

Managing and grooming BDE & Web Researcher Team Identifying new sales leads
Pitching products and/or services
Maintaining fruitful relationships with existing customers

Day-to-day duties typically include:

Build long-term relationships with new and existing customers
Prepare sales contracts ensuring adherence to law-established rules and guidelines
Keep records of sales, revenue, invoices etc.
Promote the company's products/services addressing or predicting clients' objectives
Conduct research to identify new markets and customer needs
Arrange business meetings with prospective clients

Other typical duties include:

Develop a growth strategy focused both on financial gain and customer satisfaction Provide trustworthy feedback and after-sales support Develop entry level staff into valuable salespeople

Business Development Manager

X-Byte Technolabs Pvt. Ltd.

March 2017 to April 2018

Primary responsibilities:

Managing and grooming BDE & Web Researcher Team Identifying new sales leads Pitching products and/or services Maintaining fruitful relationships with existing customers

Day-to-day duties typically include:

Bidding on almost all online marketplace portals like Upwork, Freelancer, Fever, Guru.com etc. Researching organizations and individuals online (especially on social media) to identify new leads and potential new markets

Researching the needs of other companies and learning who makes decisions about purchasing

Contacting potential clients via email or phone to establish rapport and set up meetings Planning and overseeing new marketing initiatives

Attending conferences, meetings, and industry events

Other typical duties include:

Preparing PowerPoint presentations and sales displays
Contacting clients to inform them about new developments in the company's products
Developing quotes and proposals
Negotiating and renegotiating by phone, email, and in person
Developing sales goals for the team and ensuring they are met
Training personnel and helping team members develop their skills

Business Development Manager

Alice Infoweb Pvt. Ltd.

April 2015 to March 2017

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for Generating Web/mobileapplications design, development leads through various perspectives.
- Bidding on almost all online marketplace portals like Upwork, Freelancer, Fever, Guru.com etc.
- Understanding Client requirements & responsible for the planning, management, coordination and financial control of all the Projects.
- Taking Follow-up with business leads to generate leads for new business and preparing new proposal by making presentations and convincing clients for contracts.
- Locating or proposing potential business deals by contacting potential partners; discovering and exploring opportunities. Market Research and looking for new business opportunities.
- Negotiating commercials and closing business deals.
- Meeting cost standards by monitoring expenses; implementing cost-saving actions.
- Screening potential business deals by analyzing market strategies, deal requirements, potential, and financials; evaluating options.
- Enhancing organization reputation by accepting ownership for accomplishing new and different requests; exploring opportunities to add value to job accomplishments.
- Coordinating with technical departments for deal finalization.

Project Manager

Karma Source

Jan 2014 to April 2015

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for overseeing the set up, construction, implementation, and completion
 of a website.
- Managing the team of designers, developers and programmers and follow our step by step system.
- Acting as a service associate/liaison between the client and support staff.
- Gathering all necessary information from the client before the construction of a site begins and coordinate with the designers, developers and programmers.
- Ensuring that all tasks are being completed correctly and on time by support staff.
- During implementation, I ask to help troubleshoot a variety issues brought up by the support staff or the client.
- During Completion, I instruct the client how to use their website back office tools.
- Remain in constant contact with the client and advocates for the sites completion in a specified time frame throughout the entire process.

Sr. Researcher

Responsibilities

- Research market conditions in National & International area to determine potential sales of product or service.
- Establishing research methodology and designs format for data gathering, such as surveys, opinion polls, or questionnaires.
- Conducting qualitative or quantitative surveys, which may involve field, interview or focus group assessments
- Examining and analyzing statistical data to forecast future marketing trends
- Gathering data on competitors and analyzes prices, sales, and methods of marketing and distribution.
- Collecting data on customer preferences and buying habits.
- Preparing reports and graphic illustrations of findings.

Central Reservation Executive (E-1)

Neesa Leisure Ltd.

Cambay Spa & Golf Resort

Jan 2010 to Aug 2012

Responsibilities

- As a Central Reservation Executive, I was taking care of the Bookings & Member reservation.
- I used to process emails in regard to send the package details & confirmation details in regard to their bookings.
- I ensured that each customer should get a complete resolution and explanation in regards to their query or problem.
- I was taking calls of Centralized Toll free customer care of Cambay Resorts.

Process Associate

AZURE Knowledge Corporation Pvt. Ltd. 2010

April 2007 to Jan

Responsibilities

- As a Process Associate, I was into the process of U.S. Mortgage Refinance & Debt Settlement Campaigns
- Calling the U.S. residents for refinancing their Mortgage & settling their debts
- I used to take necessary information from the customer & transfer (Hot Transfer) their call to our client in U.S. at the same time
- It was totally a hard core Sales process of Lead generation

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor in Commerce from Sardar Patel University (SPU) in 2008